peoplesclimate.org 2017-04-28

# Peoples Climate Movement 2017 – Privacy

_Privacy Policy Last Updated on 7 April, 2016_

This web site (the “Web Site”) is operated by People’s Climate Movement (“we”, “us” and/or “our”) and has been created to accomplish our mission of building a global movement to solve the climate crisis with the help of Web Site visitors (“you”, “your”). This Privacy Policy sets forth our policy with respect to information that is collected from you.

**General Policy:** People’s Climate Movement has a firm commitment to internet privacy. You can visit most portions of People’s Climate Movement without telling us who you are and without revealing any personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”). The only information we collect from a normal Web Site visit is information that cannot be used to specifically identify you (“Non-Personal Information”), which usually includes the name of your internet service provider, the browser and type of machine you are using, the web site that referred you to us, the pages you request and the date and time you request them.

**Personal Information:   **The only time we collect Personal Information is when you voluntarily provide such information, such as when you contact us with inquiries, respond to one of our surveys, or register to participate in certain projects or campaigns. Wherever we collect Personal Information we make an effort to provide a link to this Privacy Policy. We do encourage you to voluntarily share Personal Information with us, because we can’t build the movement we need to win the fight against global warming without you.  By voluntarily providing us with Personal Information, you are consenting to our use of it in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

##### How We Use the Information:

**Non-Personal Information:   **We use the Non-Personal Information collected to generate statistics and measure Web Site activity in order to improve the quality of our Web Site for our visitors.

**Personal Information:** We use the Personal Information you provide in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. If you provide Personal Information for a certain reason, we may use the Personal Information in connection with the reason for which it was provided.  For example, if you sign up for a campaign, we will use your Personal Information to send you updates and other information about the campaign. Similarly, if a local leader starts a campaign or petition that you sign, they may access the information you have shared and follow up with you about local campaign updates.  If we intend on using any Personal Information in any manner that is not consistent with this Privacy Policy, we will inform you of the anticipated use before the Personal Information is collected.

**Aggregated Personal Information:   **In an ongoing effort to accomplish our mission and understand Web Site visitors better, People’s Climate Movement may conduct research on its visitor’s demographics and interests based on the Personal Information and other information provided to us. This research may be compiled and analyzed on an aggregate basis, and People’s Climate Movement may share this aggregate information with its affiliates and allies. People’s Climate Movement may also disclose aggregated visitor statistics in order to describe the size, scope, and demographics of its network. This aggregate information does not identify you personally.

**Storage:   **Both Personal Information and Non-Personal Information collected in accordance with this Privacy Policy may be stored by People’s Climate Movement itself or it may be included in databases owned and maintained by our affiliates, agents or service providers.

**Donor Privacy Policy:** People’s Climate Movement does not rent, share, sell or trade any Personal Information from online or offline donations with any 2nd or 3rd party except People’s Climate Movement Action Fund. In addition, we do not rent, share, sell or trade information about what donations supporters have undertaken on our Web site with any 2nd or 3rd party except for People’s Climate Movement Action Fund.

**When We Share the Information** :

People’s Climate Movement is not interested in selling your information. We consider this information to be a vital part of our relationship with you. There are, however, certain circumstances in which we may share your Personal Information with certain third parties without further notice to you, as set forth below:

**Affiliates and Allies:** We may share your name and/or email address with trusted organizations that share our mission to solve the climate crisis. These organizations include the People’s Climate Movement Action Fund (People’s Climate Movement’s affiliate organization) and partner organizations that may be organizing climate action events in your area. We will not share your information with any individual or organization who is not engaged in furthering the success of People’s Climate Movement.

**Action and Signup Pages:   **We do not share the information you’ve given us on Action and Signup pages with unaffiliated groups or individuals without your explicit permission. For petitions, letters to the editor, and surveys you’ve signed or completed, we treat your name, city, state, and comments as public information. We will not make your street address publicly available, but we may transmit it campaign targets specifically noted on the signup page.

**Agents, Consultants and Related Third Parties:** People’s Climate Movement sometimes hires other companies to perform certain functions. Examples of such functions include mailing information, maintaining databases, and processing payments. When we employ another company to perform a function of this nature, we take precautions to provide them with the information that they need to perform their specific function.

**Legal Requirements:** We may disclose your Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (i) comply with a legal obligation, (ii) protect and defend the rights or property of People’s Climate Movement, (iii) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of Web Site visitors or the public, or (iv) protect against legal liability.

**Account Creation:** By registering an account/password/event for a “day of action”, we may also create an account for you on affiliated platforms so you can easily manage future local events in your community.

**Security:** People’s Climate Movement makes great efforts to protect the Personal Information provided via the Web Site from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. However, no Internet or e-mail transmission is ever fully secure or error free. In particular, e-mail sent to or from the Web Site may not be secure. Therefore, you should take special care in deciding what information you send to us via e-mail.

People’s Climate Movement also strives to insure the secure collection and transmission of sensitive visitor payment information using industry accepted data collection and encryption methodologies. If you choose to make a donation to People’s Climate Movement, your credit card information will be used only for transactions through our secure online payment system. If you choose to make that donation recurring, the information will be stored by our third party payment processors, and is not stored or seen by People’s Climate Movement. People’s Climate Movement does not sell or otherwise disclose such visitor payment information outside the organization.

**Updates and Email Tracking:** If you sign up to receive updates from People’s Climate Movement, we will strive to provide you accurate and timely information about our campaign activities. In order to improve our engagement with our network, we may track whether the emails we send to you are being opened and whether the links they contain are being clicked. While the vast majority of communications will come to you direct from People’s Climate Movement, some may come from the People’s Climate Movement Action Fund or other trusted People’s Climate Movement allies in special cases—such as organizing events that further People’s Climate Movement’s mission in your area.

**Cookies:** Like most web sites, People’s Climate Movement may place a “cookie,” or small file, in the browser files of a visitor’s computer. We use cookies to save information you give us so that you don’t have to re-enter it each time you visit our Web Site. This allows us to personalize the Web Site to your taste and provide the best web experience possible to our visitors.

In addition, People’s Climate Movement enables the use of the Adobe Flash Player. Adobe’s Flash Player is used by the vast majority of web sites that offer video and other interactive content. By default, your use of the Adobe Flash Player generates “flash cookies”. The Adobe Flash Player (and similar applications) use flash cookies to remember user settings, preferences and usage similar to the browser cookies referenced above.

**Updating the Privacy Policy:** People’s Climate Movement does reserve the right to change its policy at any time and from time to time without prior notice as necessary to support the movement.  Please review this Privacy Policy periodically, and especially before you provide any Personal Information. This Privacy Policy was last updated on the date indicated above. Your continued use of the Web Site after any changes are made to this Privacy Policy indicates your agreement with the terms of the changed Privacy Policy.

**Exclusions:** This Privacy Policy only applies to information collected by People’s Climate Movement through the Web Site.  The Privacy Policy does not apply to any unsolicited information provided to People’s Climate Movement through the Web Site or through any other means. This includes, but is not limited to, information posted to any public areas of the Web Site and any unsolicited submissions. All such information will be treated as public information.

**Links to Other Web Sites:**   This Privacy Policy applies only to the Web Site. The Web Site may contain links to other web sites not operated or controlled by People’s Climate Movement (the “Third Party Sites”). The policies and procedures we described here do not apply to the Third Party Sites. The links from the Web Site do not imply that People’s Climate Movement endorses or has reviewed the Third Party Sites. We suggest contacting those sites directly for information on their privacy policies.

**Social Media:**  Through the Web Site, you can choose to access certain social media web sites and services that are owned and controlled by third parties (e.g. Facebook and Twitter) (the “Social Media Services”). When you elect to access and use the Social Media Services, you will be sharing your information (which will include personal information if you elect to share such information) with those Social Media Services. As with other Third Party Sites, the information that you share with the Social Media Services will be governed by the privacy policies and terms of service of the providers of such Social Media Services and not by the policies and procedures we describe here.
